<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<experiences>
    <experience id="exp001">
        <title>Technology Instructor</title>
        <company>Robertson College (contract)</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>Jan 2025</start_date>
        <end_date>Present</end_date>
        <role_type>Online Instructor-Guided (Complementary Learning)</role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Instructed 20 course offerings across 12 subjects for Full Stack Development (FSD) and Data Analytics (DA) diploma programs.</achievement>
            <achievement>Courses taught: C# Programming, .NET, ASP .NET, ASP .NET Core, Object-oriented Programming (Java), Front End Frameworks, Intro to JavaScript, Web Development Basics, Data Collection, Testing and Quality Assurance, Version Control with Git and GitHub, Introduction to IT.</achievement>
            <achievement>Deliver a minimum of 3 synchronous live sessions per week per course, hosting live coding sessions and debugging student projects in real-time.</achievement>
            <achievement>Manage and maintain a GitHub repository hosting open-source course materials and sample code.</achievement>
            <achievement>Archive session recordings for asynchronous review and participate in ongoing monthly instructor training seminars.</achievement>
            <achievement>Maintained an average student satisfaction rating of 4.5/5.0 across evaluated courses, with feedback highlighting approachability, real-world teaching approach, and responsiveness.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>C#, .NET, ASP .NET Core, Java, JavaScript, React, Front End Frameworks, Git, GitHub, Azure, SQL, Testing and QA, Data Collection</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp002">
        <title>Senior Software Developer</title>
        <company>bitHeads Inc.</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2022</start_date>
        <end_date>2025</end_date>
        <role_type></role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Developed and maintained cross-platform client SDKs for brainCloud BaaS, enabling gamification, leaderboards, matchmaking, lobbies, real-time multiplayer, and cloud code for 50+ published games across 12 platforms including PlayStation, Xbox, Nintendo Switch, Steam, iOS, and Android.</achievement>
            <achievement>Primary focus on C++ client SDK, Unreal Engine plugin, iOS (Objective-C/Swift), Android Native (Java/Kotlin), and PlayStation; reviewed and debugged all other supported platforms and languages.</achievement>
            <achievement>Built and maintained Unreal Engine sample projects including Space Shooter, Target Practice, Tappy Chicken, Relay Blast, and dedicated server demo to help onboard client studios.</achievement>
            <achievement>Supported integration for notable titles including SUPERHOT VR (SUPERHOT Team), Tony Hawk's Skate Jam (Maple Media), Crypt of the NecroDancer (Brace Yourself Games), and Invizimals (PlayStation Mobile).</achievement>
            <achievement>Engineered and maintained CI/CD and TDD pipelines ensuring high-quality multi-platform releases.</achievement>
            <achievement>Designed and built demonstration applications and accompanying widget libraries for every supported client platform to showcase SDK capabilities — UI frameworks spanned Dear ImGui (C++), Unreal Engine UMG, SwiftUI/UIKit (iOS), Android Views (Java/Kotlin), Unity (C#), and PlayStation SDK.</achievement>
            <achievement>Hired in part for educational background — role required teaching clients one-on-one how to use the API, strong documentation skills, and ability to develop academic examples and demonstrations.</achievement>
            <achievement>Responded to customer issues and feature requests directly, maintaining strong relationships with AAA and Indie studio clients.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>Unreal Engine, C++, Objective-C, Swift, iOS, Android Native, Java, Kotlin, PlayStation, Nintendo Switch, Xbox, Node.js, Groovy, C# (Unity, Godot), Shell Script, MacOS, Windows, Linux</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp003">
        <title>Co-founder / Lead Developer / Instructor</title>
        <company>Silicon Hanna Inc. (self-employed; founded as SuRJE Software Solutions Inc.)</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2005</start_date>
        <end_date>2022</end_date>
        <role_type>Self-employed; operated concurrently with full-time employment at BJ Pipeline (2005–2008) and Fekete Associates (2008–2011); primary focus from 2011 until joining bitHeads in 2022. Company founded as SuRJE Software Solutions Inc. (Swarms under Ricardo and Joanne using Evolution — a nod to graduate research in agent-based systems); renamed Silicon Hanna Inc. upon relocating the studio to Hanna, Alberta.</role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Designed, coded, and published eleven games to commercial app stores for mobile devices — including Star Chase and Bitsy (2008, physics-based iOS games released under the SuRJE name) and nine further titles (2011–2022) under the Silicon Hanna brand.</achievement>
            <achievement>Developed course curriculum and instructed intermediate C++ programming for the University of Calgary Department of Continuing Education; prepared well-organised lectures, sample code, and assignments; received positive student feedback.</achievement>
            <achievement>Technical writing, web development, Google Maps and Firebase integration, and server administration.</achievement>
            <achievement>Explored cutting-edge device technologies and SDKs including ARKit augmented reality, Chipmunk physics, and Unreal Engine.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>Unreal Engine, Objective-C, Swift, iOS, Android Native, Kotlin, Augmented Reality, ARKit, C++, OpenGL, PHP, SQL, MacOS, Windows, Linux</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp004">
        <title>Tools Programmer</title>
        <company>Fekete Associates Inc. (S&amp;P Global)</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2008</start_date>
        <end_date>2011</end_date>
        <role_type></role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Developed tools using mathematical models to maximize production and improve efficiency for major oil &amp; gas corporations.</achievement>
            <achievement>Contributed to the company's shared UI tools library — the MFC-based component library used as the foundation for all internal development projects, ensuring consistent interaction patterns and visual design across the product suite.</achievement>
            <achievement>Led research on a new system that reduced build times by 40%.</achievement>
            <achievement>Designed and delivered a voluntary OpenGL elective course for colleagues using the OpenGL Programming Guide as the core reference — covered the rendering pipeline, viewing projections, z-buffering, and geometric transformations; students built an interactive OpenGL widget within the company's custom MFC framework as a capstone project; accommodated both beginner programmers and senior developers; received positive response from students and senior staff.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>C++, MFC, Windows</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp005">
        <title>Intermediate Software Engineer</title>
        <company>BJ Pipeline Inspection Services Inc. (Baker Hughes)</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2005</start_date>
        <end_date>2008</end_date>
        <role_type></role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Visualized in-line inspection device data using OpenGL graphics for Vectra and Gemini 3D analysis products used by pipeline analysts and engineers.</achievement>
            <achievement>Implemented neural network algorithms for automated anomaly detection.</achievement>
            <achievement>Ported an Excel-based reporting workflow to a full LAMP web application — interactive JavaScript forms, dynamic charts, and interactive geographic maps — dramatically improving accessibility and usability of inspection data for non-technical stakeholders.</achievement>
            <achievement>Improved low-level C++ algorithms for high-performance data preprocessing.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>C++, C, OpenGL, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, Neural Networks, LAMP, Borland, Windows, Linux</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp007">
        <title>Software Researcher / Lead Developer</title>
        <company>PlayStarMusic Corp.</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2005</start_date>
        <end_date>2006</end_date>
        <role_type>Concurrent with early BJ Pipeline tenure</role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Designed and built the end-user interface for a media streaming storefront — browsing, playback controls, purchase flow, and seamless DRM integration that kept the listening experience uninterrupted.</achievement>
            <achievement>Lead developer and system administrator for the full platform stack (iTunes-like storefront, DRM encoding pipeline, video streaming).</achievement>
            <achievement>Developed a prototype for a competitive search engine.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>C++, PHP, Javascript, .NET, Windows, Linux</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp008">
        <title>Junior Software Engineer</title>
        <company>Codefast.com</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2004</start_date>
        <end_date>2005</end_date>
        <role_type></role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Primary mandate was building graphical user interfaces for existing command-line tools — translating CLI workflows into usable, discoverable desktop applications.</achievement>
            <achievement>Ported applications across GUI libraries (Qt, Wx), ensuring consistent look-and-feel and interaction behaviour under a new UI framework.</achievement>
            <achievement>Developed user interfaces for software lifecycle automation tooling.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>C++, Qt, Wx, Shell script, Windows, Unix</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>

    <experience id="exp009">
        <title>Research Assistant</title>
        <company>VLab Computer Graphics Group / Artificial Intelligence Research Hub</company>
        <location></location>
        <start_date>2001</start_date>
        <end_date>2004</end_date>
        <role_type></role_type>
        <achievements>
            <achievement>Developed graphics software tools used fractal math and biological modelling.</achievement>
            <achievement>Managed network setup and code base for distributed computing.</achievement>
            <achievement>Participated in interdepartmental projects and published five research papers.</achievement>
            <achievement>Served as teaching assistant for both introductory first-year and advanced third-year courses — supplemented instructor lesson plans with independent presentations, code and math walk-throughs; received positive student feedback.</achievement>
        </achievements>
        <technologies>C++, OpenGL, Solaris, MacOS, Unix, Linux, PHP, MySQL, Qt</technologies>
        <tags></tags>
    </experience>
</experiences>
